SOLDIER OVER PA: Unit Christmas rations
must be picked up by 0900 hours.
Armor group tree decoration team,
report to the Engineering Depot.
My son, will you turn off
that wretched puppet?
Brush your teeth.
Don't call him a puppet.
I beg your pardon.
Look, he's not a puppet.
Howdy Doody's real.
Well... He's real.
Mr. Deedee Doodoo will
have to say good night.
Oh, no.
And remember, you
have to be asleep
when he comes down the chimney.
It's not even a chimney, Pop.
He has his ways.
Then I want to wait up.
Watch him do it.
Nonsense.
(SIGHS)
Okay. I want a story then.
Oh, no, no, no. No
stories tonight.
J ust one. And then
I'll go to bed.
Right away.
Then I'll brush my
teeth, I promise.
"It is said that at
the dawn of time,"
"man, beast and all magical beings lived
together under Aiglin the Father Tree."
"But man had been created
with a hole in his heart,"
"a hole that no possession,
power or knowledge could fill."
"And in his infinite greed,"
"man dreamt of expanding his
dominion over the entire Earth."
(ROARS)
(ALL SHOUTING)
"The blood of many an
elf, ogre and goblin"
was spilled in their
war with man.
"And King Balor, the
one-armed king of Elf land,"
"watched the slaughter
in dread and despair."
"But one day, the master
of the goblin blacksmiths"
"offered to build the king
a golden mechanical army,"
"seventy times 70 soldiers"
"that would never know hunger
and could not be stopped."
"Prince Nuada begged
his father to agree."
"'Build me this army,
' the king said."
"So a magical crown was forged"
"that would allow
those of royal blood"
"to command the Golden
Army if unchallenged."
"'I am King Balor, leader
of the Golden Army."
"'Is there anyone who
disputes my right?'."
"And in his throne room no
one challenged his word."
But, wait, what if someone
could challenge him?
Would they have a fight?
Well, most likely.
A challenge must be answered.
But do you want to hear the
end of this story or not?
Yes, please.
Right.
"So the world was changed, and the
next time the humans marched,"
"they felt the earth tremble
beneath their feet"
"and saw the sky darken
with monstrous shapes."
"The Golden Army had no remorse,
felt no loyalty or pain."
"And King Balor's heart
grew heavy with regret."
"So he called a truce and divided
the crown in three pieces,"
"one for the humans,
and two for himself."
"In exchange, man would
keep to the cities"
"and the magical beings
would own the forests."
"This truce would be honored by their
sons and the sons of their sons"
"until the end of time."
"But Prince Nuada did not believe
in the promises of man."
"And it is said that
he went into exile,"
"vowing to return the day his
people needed him most."
"So the Golden
Army lay dormant,"
"locked inside the
Earth, waiting."
"And there it is to this day,"
"awaiting the day the crown
is made whole again."
"Silent, still and
indestructible."
Wow. What does it
mean "industrable"?
Indestructible.
Indestruct...
it means no one
can destroy them.
Wow.
Go to sleep, my son.
But it's just a
story, right, Pops?
Is it now?
(CHUCKLES) Yeah, come on.
Those guys, they can't be real.
Well, my son, I'm
sure you'll find out.
(WINK GROWLS)
How long have you been
there, my friend?
They're over there.
I bought them today.
(TOOTH FAIRIES SQUEAKING)
I haven't fed them at all.
I will go up first.
You will follow.
And remember, Mr. Wink,
don't be shy.
(GROWLING)
(WINK ROARS)
(HORN BLARING)
(GAVEL TAPPING)
Next lot. Number 776.
This is an important
votive figure,
a fertility goddess dating
approximately 15,000 to 10,000 B .C.
(CHATTERING)
This was found in a less deposit
in a terrace about 30 meters
from the Shannon River.
And we'll open the
bidding at $300,000.
Three hundred thousand.
Three hundred and
twenty-five, thank you.
fifty, thank you.
Three seventy-five.
Three hundred and
seventy-five.
Going once. Going twice.
Sold.
And now we move on to
our next item, lot 777,
(DOOR OPENS)
a piece of the Royal
Crown of Bethmoora.
The origin of this
piece harkens back
to the saga of the
Sons of the Earth
and the creation of the
fabled Golden Army.
And here it is, our next item.
WOMAN OVER PA: Lot 777.
(CHATTERING)
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
please keep your seats.
The auction will
restart shortly.
I'm sure this is just a
temporary loss of power.
Now, for the first
time at auction,
a piece of the Royal
Crown of Bethmoora,
coming to us from a
long lost culture.
NUADA: Lost?
Not at all.
Forgotten by you, perhaps,
but very, very much alive.
AUCTIONEER: Who are you, sir?
Sir, please identify yourself.
You can't just...
I am Prince Nuada Silverlance,
son of King Balor.
And I am here, sir, to reclaim
what is rightfully mine.
Security. Call security!
(WINK GROWLS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ROARS)
(ALL SCREAM)
What do you think you're doing?
This is outrageous.
Take what you want.
Please leave.
Anything, take anything.
Be quiet.
(SHOUTS) Sit down!
Proud, empty, hollow
things that you are.
Let this remind you why
you once feared the dark.
Fishstick. We have to talk.
MANNING: Undercover.
Can't he get the
meaning of the word?
Look, we are still
government-funded.
We are still a secret, although
a dirty secret, if you ask me.
Officially we do not
exist, you see.
So that's the problem
when we get these.
Subway. Highway. Park.
And he posed for this one
and gave an autograph.
I suppress each photo.
Cell phone videos.
They cost me a fortune and
they show up on YouTube.
God, I hate YouTube.
Well, he just wants the world
outside to know what we do,
what he does.
He loathes me.
I don't think so.
No?
Target practice.
Oh, dear.
And then he posts them around.
Do you know how
that makes me feel?
(ROARS)
What's going on?
Oh, it's Friday.
I tell you, Fishstick,
he hates me.
He's out to destroy me.
My street cred is low.
Street cred?
My mojo.
Washington, they're wondering
if I've got the stuff.
You think I have an easy job?
(STAMMERING) Do you think I
enjoy being a pain in the neck?
(STUTTERING)
I am medicated.
I mean, this is not candy.
This is... it's an antacid.
Yes, it's an
over-the-counter medicine,
but this is medicine.
You see, I worry
because, you know,
I mean, I am, we are, after all,
we're just humble
public servants.
It's not about you.
He's acting out.
Things are a little
tense with Liz.
Tense? How tense? Tense how?
Well, you know, the usual.
A new couple making adjustments.
They argue. They argue, huh?
Sometimes. How bad?
Like everybody else.
They have good
days and bad days.
LIZ: I'm not done with you.
(GASPS)
Hey, Abe.
LIZ: Red, come back here!
Manning.
LIZ: Pick up your clothes!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
LIZ: Put away your things!
(SIGHS)
HELLBOY: Watch it,
boys, she's on fire.
Then again, there are
the really bad days.
I'm not afraid of you, you know.
LIZ: You should be. Look at this mess.
Look around.
I have one rule. Don't
touch my stuff.
LIZ: Oh, I get it. That's your rule.
Okay.
The one and only. I'm easy.
How's that even possible?
Everything is your stuff.
The same CD, LP.
It's Al Green.
You can't listen
to Al Green on CD.
But it's good to keep.
And an eight-track.
An eight-track, Red?
Yeah, well, one day, the world's
gonna realize its mistake.
Eight-track was the
way to go, baby.
Come on, kids, you
can come out now.
That's right, it's all over.
That's right.
And what about me, Red?
I need some space.
(EXHALES)
At least enough to
find my toothbrush.
Toothbrush? Wait a minute.
It's right there.
Red! I can't live like this.
(ALARM SOUNDING)
MAN ON PA: Security
breach central Manhattan.
Oh, damn.
Gotta go. We all gotta go.
It's an emergency, right?
MAN ON PA: Security breach.
Let's go.
MANNING: Red. Red!
MAN ON PA: All personnel
to garage area.
Hold on a sec.
Oh, jeez, it's Manning.
Watch yourself, Liz.
Red. Red!
Listen.
Manning. HI.
We're going to
downtown Manhattan.
Yeah, it'll be fun.
Downtown. Very dangerous.
Dangerous for you.
And for me.
Now, I know you dream
of the outside world,
but, trust me, it's
not that great.
It's savage, as a matter of fact.
Bad.
LIZ: Come on, fellas, let's
get this out of here.
These, on the other
hand, are good.
Mmm.
Cuban.
Good.
Being seen?
Bad.
Exactly. I confiscated a box of
these, and I'll get you some more.
But you've gotta do me a little
favor tonight, out there.
You have to be... You
have to be very, very...
Discreet.
What? Thank you. Yes.
You're welcome.
Discreet.
Invisible. In and out.
Really? Hey.
Hey, I can be discreet
if I wanna be.
I followed you and
Myers, didn't I?
And then you had him
transferred to Antarctica.
That's very discreet.
He said he liked the cold.
Like a shadow.
AGENT OVER PA: Red
team, Red team.
Like a shadow in the night.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
MANNING: US Customs discovered
a few illegally imported items.
It's a minor infraction.
And a gas pocket.
They detected a gas
pocket up there.
Now FBI agents,
under my command,
are going up there right now
with special gas equipment.
Jeez, it stinks in here.
This is worse than my room.
AGENT: Waiting for
a report on that.
Say "cheese."
(CAMERA CLICKS)
Let's go.
(CLINKING)
Whatever they called
us for is over.
We had over 70 guests reported.
We have no survivors, no bodies.
Same story here, babe.
LIZ: Don't call me "babe."
"Abe," I said. "Abe."
Wrong channel.
(EXHALES)
Abe, I think Liz is
still mad at me.
LIZ: Still the same channel.
Oh!
HELLBOY: Can I ask
you a question?
No.
Now, listen. When
we get home later,
I'm gonna clean
up my whole mess.
That's not the problem.
What is it?
Not now.
(GROANS)
Abe, what have you got?
Oh, this is interesting.
Both boxes have the Royal Seal.
Only delivered at a time of war.
Red? We have company.
HELLBOY: Come on, Blue, give me
something to work with here.
Burrowing creatures.
How many of them?
ABE: Many.
There are no corpses because
there are no leftovers.
Have you noticed the floor?
Oh, crap.
ABE: Precisely.
All these things
do is eat and eat.
Then poop, and then eat again.
Remind you of anyone?
Damn it, Abe. What
are these things?
(ABE READING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
HELLBOY: English, English.
Oh, they're Tooth Fairies.
Ha!
No, no. Third century,
Black Forest.
Feed mostly on calcium,
bones, skin, organs.
But they do go for
the teeth first.
Hence the name Tooth Fairies.
LIZ: I bet you they don't
leave money, either.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Oh, my God.
Liz, you're pregnant.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
What have you got, Marble?
Think I may have found one.
But he's kind of cute.
HELLBOY: Don't go near it!
It's biting me!
Marble.
(GROANS) it hurts! It hurts!
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
LIZ: Red, we need you here!
Marble.
(SCREAMING)
Nasty little...
Keep firing, Abe. Keep firing!
Damn.
(GROANS)
Sorry, lady.
You should be running.
There's a safe upstairs.
How do we get there?
We need a clearing.
Run!
Up to the safe, now!
LIZ: Abe. U p the stairs.
Come on, Liz, burn them all.
Go. Go!
Yes, we're going!
HELLBOY: Get in the safe, Abe.
Get in the safe!
Oh, no, no.
No, no, no!
Steel!
(SCREAMING)
Damned beasts.
Fire is mine.
Fire is in me.
Red, stay away from the window!
Fire is me.
Stop biting me!
(GROANS)
(SLOWLY) Fire is me.
World, here I come.
(GROANS)
(ALL SCREAM)
(CHATTERING)
(GUNSHOT)
What have you done?
Guess we're out.
REPORTER: Hey,
Hellboy, over here.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
CHAMBERLAIN: Your
Royal Highness.
(CHAMBERLAI N SPEAKING GAELIC)
Before entering the
council chamber,
you must surrender your weapon.
I will not.
(ROARS)
it is protocol, sire, for
peasant and prince alike.
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
(NUALA SPEAKING GAELIC)
For you, Sister,
anything.
According to multiple eye witnesses,
lives were, in fact, endangered.
There you have it, Hellboy.
But is he really on our side?
Do you have superpowers?
Well, yeah.
But, really, all I wanna be
is just an ordinary person,
just like you and
you and everybody.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, guys. You're
missing this.
We're on TV.
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
ABE: Liz. Liz, are
you all right?
Yeah, I'll be out in a minute.
You don't need to do that.
You can trust me.
My readings are quite accurate.
Shut up, Abe.
Get your damn hand
away from the door.
You have nothing to fear.
In spite of appearances,
I believe Red would be an
excellent father figure.
And what about this guy?
Walking around with a
toilet seat on his head.
A toilet seat!
It's quite obvious it's
a breathing apparatus.
Hey, I think we gotta
lose the garbage truck.
Sends out the wrong signal.
(LAUGHING)
You think that's our problem?
Transportation?
And this girl, we definitely have
to find out what's wrong with her.
She's cute, though. We
should get her on the show.
I hate it when
people stare at me.
Makes me feel like a freak.
You had no right, Red.
It's Manning. Could you...
How many times do I
have to tell you?
It's a gas pocket.
And a gaseous phenomenon
that occurred...
Gas pocket. What an idiot.
You've murdered me.
You have murdered me.
You have ridiculed me.
And you have brought
this unto yourself.
What?
Washington is sending
down a new BPRD agent.
A new guy?
Why?
To look after you.
Sire, please.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
To set us free. All
of us, Father.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
A truce based on shame.
The humans have
forgotten the gods,
destroyed the Earth.
And for what?
Parking lots. Shopping malls.
Greed has burned a hole in their
heart that will never be filled.
They will never have enough.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
Honor?
Look at this place. Where
is the honor in it?
Father, you were once
a proud warrior.
When did you become their pet?
I have returned from
exile to wage war
and reclaim our land,
our birthright.
And for that, I will call upon
the help of all of my people.
And they will answer,
the good, the bad
and the worst.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
Perhaps I am. Perhaps
they made me so.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
We will not fade.
it is.
I am sorry, Father.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
And you, Sister, are you at
peace with your king's verdict?
I am, my brother. I am.
Then very well. Death it is.
(GASPS)
(CRl ES)
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
Now, for the final
piece, my sister.
Where is she, Wink?
Where is she?
NUADA: Go find her.
Now! Find her!
(WINK ROARS)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Elevator
arriving now to section 42.
Elevator arriving
now to section 42.
Pardon me, boys. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Is he here? Not yet.
I'm telling you, we
don't need this guy.
Well, I think we do.
Evidently, this guy's quite
the big shot in Washington.
What's his name?
His name is Johann Krauss.
Johann Krauss? Sounds German.
He's the top man in...
Ectoplasmic.
Yes, thank you.
Ectoplasmic research.
Comes highly recommended
by our European liaison.
Johann Krauss. "Liaison ."
I love that word, don't you?
It's so hoity toity.
I don't like Germans.
No fingerprints.
Here he comes. Germans
make me nervous.
No photo. Dossier says, and I
translate, "He has a nice open face."
Oh, my God.
Damen und Herren, Johann
Krauss at your service.
I like him.
Look at that. Poor
little thing.
Bought and sold on
the black market.
Crammed into cargo containers.
Smuggled, abused.
He has very expressive hands.
The seal on the box
worries me also.
A warring emblem.
Yes, from the Bethmoora clan.
The Sons of the Earth.
Your file says you're the
brains of the operation,
and I must admit, I'm impressed.
In my file, you'll
see, Mr. Krauss,
that I worked very closely
with Abe in his training.
Ja, okay.
Let's see what our little
friend here can remember.
Memory gets a little sketchy right
after you've burned to death.
But maybe Saint
Malachy can help.
Oh, no, no. No
amulets, Mein Herr.
Teleplasty.
Plastic. Very modern.
Teleplasty by which an
ectoplasmic medium,
such as Dr. Krauss, can
control inanimate things,
organic, mechanical,
dead or alive.
JOHANN: Take it, take
it all in, mein Junge.
(SCREAMS)
There we are. Get up.
Get up. Get up.
Now I have full control
of its limbic system.
Let us see how long
I can hold it.
(CHATTERS)
What?
Hey, you chewed off
the tip of my tail.
Yeah, you, you little...
it says you're rude, brutish
und not very bright.
Wow!
(CHATTERING)
it seems our little friend here
remembers market
sounds and voices.
And a peculiar troll
language spoken
in the last place his
cage was opened.
The troll market.
The troll market? Come on.
No one's ever found it.
That's because it doesn't exist.
(CHOKES)
Mr. Krauss? Dr. Krauss, sir.
Our little informant there
doesn't look so good.
(COUGHING)
Back inside, you.
There we are.
So, now we know where to begin.
Trolls dwell under bridges.
Wow. You're a genius.
By the way, there's over 2,000
bridges in New York City.
But Vladimir Vanya, 19th
century occult historian,
places the troll
market directly under
the east end of the
Brooklyn Bridge.
We've already looked there.
Yes, you have, but
not with me, Agent.
Not with me.
We're moving in.
Keep it coming, keep it coming.
Hold it.
"Not with me, Agent."
What an ego.
I like him.
Well, you can keep him.
I mean, am I the only one that
thinks this guy is full of...
No, no, no, no, don't lean.
Lot 336, the Schufftein glasses.
Could it be?
The three surviving pairs,
and we will use them to
locate the troll market.
Dr. Krauss, what a coup.
The Schufftein glasses.
You're my hero.
Hey. You Hellboy?
Yeah.
You're ugly, man.
Two more on the
wall in front of me
and then three on the
alleys facing that way.
What do you think
of Mr. Know-it-All?
Don't know, too early to tell.
Hey, you're Hellboy.
I know, I'm ugly.
Forget it.
We'll talk about it later.
He's sure of himself, and I
think maybe you're intimidated.
Intimidated. H uh?
JOHANN: Keep us up to date on the
cameras, Agent Sherman. Over and out.
What's this?
Normally, we can't see
fairy folk and trolls.
They generate a cloaking
aura called "glamour."
But in 1878, Emil Schufftein
designed and built these.
Four crystal diopters that
penetrate that effect
and reveal the true
nature of things.
Oh, Dr. Krauss, they're more
beautiful than I'd imagined.
You must try them on then.
Oh, yes.
Try them on, Agent.
They'll look good.
I love these tight
little leather straps.
Intimidated?
(SCOFFS)
Mr. Kraut? Sir?
Krauss, Agent. With
a double "S ."
S-S . Right, right.
Listen, those gizmos?
How do you know they work?
LIZ: I have a suspect.
Give me a vector, Agent Sherman.
A vector.
B-12, the alley, northbound.
JOHANN: Well, track the target.
We're coming down.
Keep an eye on her.
I'll be right back.
This little old lady? Come on.
It's a Fragglewump, an
ugly Scottish troll.
They're afraid of canaries.
Oh, my God. Canaries, huh?
What about the kittens?
She feeds on them.
WOMAN: Come on, then.
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
That thing is a "she"?
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
(MEOWING)
Down, you fools.
What do you think you are doing?
She's gonna eat the cat.
You'll make her aware
of our presence.
ABE: We should use
the canary now.
She's gonna eat it!
ABE: We should use the
bird, Dr. Krauss.
The bird.
She's going to eat the cat.
You will stay put and
follow my orders.
I can't sit by here...
You are directly under my
command, and you have to obey.
Stay put! Oh, screw this!
Hey! Lucy.
Come back here.
I'm home.
Oh, yes, dearie.
Can I help you?
Give it up, nasty.
We can see you.
You see me?
How? How do you see me?
We're looking for the entrance
to the troll market.
Any clues?
Come any closer and
I'll rip your heart.
We're gonna have to get a
little old-school, Abe.
Give me the bird.
Not a canary.
What, you're afraid
of this little guy?
Who'd know?
No more, no more.
I'll take you there.
Come on, let's go,
you dirty old troll.
Let's go.
Agent Sherman, we are going
into the troll market.
Keep communication to a minimum.
Over and out
I like him.
You see, this is a man
who takes charge.
You think?
Yeah. He's efficient.
He's precise.
You add "resistant" to that,
you got yourself a new watch.
Dr. Krauss is aware of the
chain of command, and he...
Oh, brother!
He seems to like me.
OLD WOMAN: Here we are.
Wow, that's some door!
JOHANN: It's a complex
combination lock.
What do you think, Agent Sapien?
Not good.
With the number of symbols on the
combination, we'll be here for days.
Well, not necessarily.
Let me try my technique.
Open it, Lucy.
I will not.
Pretty please.
(SHUDDERS)
Do as you may, demon.
Release the yellow beast.
Tear my eyes out.
Rip my insides and my
legs and my tongue,
but I will never open that door.
(SCREAMS)
(LOUD CRASH)
Is that your
investigative technique?
It said "never."
it's unconscionable.
That means he didn't like it.
What?
So, what, you're gonna
show us how it's done,
Mr. By-The-Book?
Is that it?
Yes, I think I will.
There we are.
Let me see. Yes.
Gentlemen, welcome
to the troll market.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GROANS)
LIZ: Red, there's something really
important that I need to tell you.
Oh, Liz, you should be here.
You'd love it.
Nobody's looking at us.
We blend right in.
Agent, I said keep
communication to a minimum.
You'll blow our cover.
You know? I think he's right.
I'm bringing you
here for sure, babe.
The fishbowl wants radio silence.
So...
Over and out.
The Royal Seal.
Brother Red. Red,
do you read me?
Yeah, I read you, Blue, but I'm
watching Sherlock at work.
I'll get back to you.
JOHANN: Excuse me, sir.
Sir, excuse... Pardon me.
Sir, may I ask a...
CREATURE: I gotta tell
the boys that one.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Have you seen anyone purchasing
this type of Tooth Fairy?
No one sells them
down here, pal.
Over in Jersey, maybe.
Well, what about this, then?
Do you recognize this seal?
Make him go away.
No. We don't.
Please, dear sir.
You'd better go. Now!
We'll make it worth your while.
(ROARS)
Don't waste your time.
We will not talk!
What are you doing?
You're absolutely
sure about that, huh?
Absolutely.
You won't talk, eh?
Never.
Never, huh?
Never ever, ever.
(GROANS)
Feeling a little chattier now?
We'll never talk.
Yes, yes.
We will, only don't
hit me anymore.
Chicken.
Who bought the Tooth Fairies?
Prince Nuada.
They say Prince Nuada broke the truce,
and now there is talk of war,
a war with the human world.
Sorry, kid.
That's all right.
Nice baby.
I'm not a baby. I'm a tumor.
Yes, Red. I am following
a lead right now.
It may turn out...
it may turn out to be nothing,
but I will let you
know soon enough.
What do you want?
Tell me your name.
(GASPS)
Follow me.
Your father left you this map.
In it, he said, lies the secret
to the location of
the Golden Army.
(DOOR BANGING)
Move away! Quickly,
Your Highness.
Can I help you with something?
No, thank you. I'm
just looking.
You can't go in there!
NUALA: Sir, why are
you following me?
I...
I was just hoping to find an
old map chart of Algiers.
Why are you following me?
I was not.
Did my brother send you
to steal the crown piece?
Your brother?
Oh, you're sorely
mistaken, I assure you.
Then answer me truthfully.
Why were you following me?
My name is Abraham Sapien.
There is no such name.
Oh, I don't like it
either, but I...
Enough.
Give me your hand.
Your hand.
You are an agent
for the Bureau of Paranormal
Research and Defense.
And your name is...
Oh...
Horrible, I know.
I'm Nuala, Princess Nuala.
Yes, I know.
Forgive me, Your Highness,
but as you were
learning about me,
I couldn't help but learn
a bit about you myself.
I know that you need our help.
I'm afraid it's the
other way around.
(LOUD BANG)
(WINK ROARING)
The window. Out now.
I will take care of this.
Oh, dear.
(ABE SCREAMING)
Go! Now go!
(GUNSHOTS)
Get out of here, Blue.
Yes. Come with me,
Your H ighness.
You.
(ROARS)
Let me put this to you
as delicately as I can.
My cigar, it was Cuban.
Now you pissed me off.
Oh, crap.
(ROARS)
(CHATTERING)
Whoa!
(HELLBOY GRUNTING)
(LAUGHS)
(ROARING)
(GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
Now stay down!
Damn.
(ROARS)
A tooth. Happy?
Give it up, pal. It's over.
I wouldn't do that
if I were you.
Wow. Told you.
(WINK ROARS IN PAIN)
JOHANN: Oh, my God what
have you done, Agent Hellboy?
Look at this! Now
we have to leave.
Red. This is Princess Nuala.
Lady.
JOHANN: We should leave.
Now. Now!
Let's go.
(CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
To wage his war, my
brother needs this,
the final piece of the
Crown of Bethmoora
and this map to the location
of the Golden Army chamber.
The Golden Army.
The harbingers of death.
The unstoppable tide.
Howdy Doody.
Your H ighness, if you hand
the crown piece over to us...
No. Where it goes, I go.
My father died to uphold
the truce with your world.
You must honor his
noble intention.
The lady's in dire danger.
I take it you're vouching
for her, Agent Sapien?
Most emphatically. Yes, I am.
Even so.
I am sorry, but we
simply cannot assume
such responsibility on our own.
The lady just lost her father.
What more do you want?
You may not care, but there
are procedures, rules
and little handbooks...
She's coming with us.
You got that, Gas Bag?
What did you call me?
NUADA: You.
You will pay for what happened
to my friend down there.
Yeah, right. You take checks?
Demon.
Born from a womb of shadows.
Sent to destroy their world, and
you still believe you belong.
Are we gonna talk all night?
'Cause I'm really sleepy.
No, Brother, no!
Kill him.
It's just a jumping bean.
It's going for water. Hurry.
Oh, dear.
No. No, no, no, no. No.
MAN #1: What the hell is that?
AGENT: Excuse me!
MAN #2: Stay back.
MAN 3: Hey, what's going on?
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
PILOT: We've got
target in sight.
It's an Elemental,
a giver of life and a destroyer.
What?
A Forest God.
HELLBOY: A Forest God, eh?
I'm gonna get me Big Baby.
Somebody help! My baby's...
Help! Help!
How can I help you, ma'am?
My baby's inside!
Come with us, dear lady, please.
There's nothing to worry about.
We've got everything
under control.
WOMAN: Please. My baby's
still in there! Please!
(SCREAMS)
(CRYING)
Hey, little guy.
PILOT: Homing in on target.
Hang on, kid.
JOHANN: Agent Hellboy.
Reach higher ground
and shoot the weapon.
Shoot the weapon!
First praise the tail, kid.
You must shoot it in
the energy ganglion.
The what?
JOHANN: The energy ganglion.
Scheisse. The head!
Shoot it in the head!
Whoa!
Oh, crap.
You gotta trust me, little buddy.
Okay?
(CHUCKLING)
You woke up the baby.
(SCREAMING)
Agent Hellboy, take the shot!
Right now! Take it!
That's an order!
Take the shot.
That's an order, Agent Hellboy.
Shoot it! Shoot the gun!
Shoot the gun!
NUADA: Demon.
What are you waiting for?
This is what you
wanted, isn't it?
Look at it. It's the
last of its kind.
Like you and I.
You destroy it,
the world will never
see its like again.
JOHANN: Shoot it!
You have more in common
with us than with them.
JOHANN: It's breaking free.
You could be a king.
JOHANN: You will not
disobey a direct order!
Shoot it! It's getting loose!
If you cannot command...
JOHANN: Lt will
destroy everything!
That's an order, Agent Hellboy!
Then you must obey.
JOHANN: Shoot it now! Damn.
Shoot it!
AGENT: Move back.
Step back, step back.
It's beautiful.
(BABY CRYING)
(SHUSHING)
WOMAN: And this huge monster
just came out of nowhere!
(CLAMORING)
MAN: Yo, give the
baby back, man!
Oh, what have you
done to my baby?
The baby's fine.
You freak!
REPORTER: Hellboy, what'd
you do to that baby?
The baby's fine.
Don't move. Hands in the air!
Up!
He's got a weapon in his hand.
That is his hand.
Miss, stay away from him
for your own safety.
He was trying to help.
Don't you see?
He was just trying to help.
That's all we do.
That's all we've done
all these years.
REPORTER: She's
touching his hand!
We've just tried to help you.
You.
MAN #1: You're a goddamn freak.
MAN #2: We don't
need you around!
WOMAN: What a freak.
Liz.
Let's go home.
Investigation of the BPRD and its
promotion of intra-species marriage
seen by many as a threat
to traditional families,
fuelled by federal funds.
(GROANS)
I didn't touch you yet.
(WINCES)
You did a good job out there.
Then tell me, why
don't I feel so good?
I mean, I killed that thing.
And for what?
They don't even like me.
I mean, they're afraid of me.
What do we do with that?
Red, I don't want
you to freak out.
I'm gonna leave
for a little bit.
I need time to think.
About what?
Can't you do your
thinking right here?
Look, I'll be really,
really quiet.
I'll get rid of the cats.
Red, why are you with me?
Do you need everyone
to like you?
Everybody? Or am I enough?
Think about it.
You stay. We belong dead.
NUALA: It's blank.
No coordinates.
NUALA: "Be near me
when my light is low."
"When the blood creeps and the
nerves prick and tingle."
"And the heart is sick and all
the wheels of being slow."
"Be near me when the sensuous frame is
wracked with pangs that conquer trust."
"And time, a maniac..."
ABE: Tennyson, "In Memoriam
." A beautiful poem.
Forgive me, I didn't
mean to startle you.
Oh, no. No, no. I
borrowed this book.
I hope you don't mind.
Oh, no, no. Please,
this is your home now.
You are safe here.
My brother will find me.
He always does.
How could he?
Our location is a highly
classified secret.
Yes, but I know of it now,
which means that he does, too.
We're twins.
Even as children, a link has
bound us one to the other.
Something I cannot explain.
No need.
You look different.
Oh, do I?
Perhaps my hair?
No.
It's your eyes. I
can see your eyes.
Yes. Just trying a new look.
Is that a map?
Yes, it was in the cylinder.
There are no coordinates.
Perhaps there's a watermark.
You were very brave
vouching for me.
How do you know I'm not the
enemy, bringing me here?
It's as you were
saying just now.
From intuition maybe, a link.
Normally I'm able to read
others quite quickly,
but I've never met
anyone like you.
Nor I, like you.
Good night, Abraham.
Good night, Princess.
Your Highness.
Your Majesty. Your... Ma'am.
Ma'am?
Gute Nacht, Agent Hellboy.
Look, Agent, I know
you don't like me,
but I could take
away your badge.
Never had one.
Kept asking, though.
You will learn to obey
me, follow protocol
and stay fockused at all times.
Oh, that word "fockused ."
Yeah, with your accent, I
wouldn't use it that much.
I knew Professor
Broom, young man.
You didn't know Professor Broom.
Yes, I did.
After my accident...
Shut up. Shut up.
He designed this
containment suit.
A wonderful man.
And even then he was worried
about your future. He...
Hey, Gas Bag, stop it!
Right now.
Or what? Are you
threatening me?
Because I think I can take you.
Excuse me?
You heard me.
I couldn't hear you from
all the way over there.
I can take you because
you have one fatal flaw.
Oh, I wanna hear it.
No, you don't. You
can't take criticism.
Try me.
Can't take it.
(SHOUTING) What's my flaw?
Your temper. It gets
the best of you.
Makes you weak. Makes
you vulnerable.
(CHOKING)
Oh, crap.
Johann.
(GASPING)
(CHOKING)
Johann? Johann?
Hey, Johann?
Come on, pal. Hang
in there, will you?
Johann? Johann?
Damn.
(JOHANN SHOUTS)
Ow!
(JOHANN SHOUTING)
There we are.
Your temper, it
makes you sloppy.
Try to control it,
Agent Hellboy.
Before it controls you.
(SINGING IN GERMAN)
Glasshole.
Mmm.
Huh?
(SOFT ROCK MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
Hello, Red.
Well, you're up late.
What are you listening to?
Vivaldi. II cimento
dell'armonia.
I particularly like the last...
Hey, hey. What's that?
Just a remote.
This? Yes.
"Popular Love Songs."
Oh, Abe.
You fell for the Princess.
She's... She's like me.
A creature from another world.
You need to get out more.
She's alone in the world.
I wanna help her.
I need to care for her.
You're in love. Have a beer.
Oh, my body's a temple.
Well, now it's an
amusement park.
No, no, no.
The glandular balance of...
Just shut up and
drink it, would you?
What track? Eight.
Can't Smile Without You.
I know.
Yep, I'm gonna need a beer, too.
Well, see, I love this song.
And I can't smile or cry.
I think I have no tear ducts.
I wish Father were here.
He'd know what to tell you.
Us.
(SINGING) I can't
smile without you
I can't laugh and I can't sing
I'm finding it hard
to do anything.
You see, I feel sad
when you're sad
I feel glad when you're glad.
If you only knew what
I'm going through
I just can't smile without you.
You came along.
Just like a song.
And brightened my day.
Who'd have believed that
you were part of a dream?
Now it all seems
light years away.
And now you know I can't
smile without you
I can't smile without you.
NUADA: Nuala.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
Good dog.
MAN: Security detail for the
front gate, immediately.
It's the last one.
(SHUSHING)
HELLBOY: Look at her.
She's it, Abe.
She's it.
She's my whole wide...
You know?
Yeah. Yeah.
I would give my life for her.
But she also wants
me to do the dishes.
I would die and do the dishes.
Why is she mad at me?
It's not because
the room is dirty.
Something else.
Well, ask her, then.
No.
Listen, Abe.
Yeah.
When a woman's mad
about something,
but she's really mad
about something else,
you can't ask because then they
get angry because you had to ask.
Do you know what I mean?
Never mind, don't
answer that question.
You gotta just...
Yeah.
Find out.
(GASPS)
Very quick of you.
The parchment.
It was of no importance.
The cylinder is
very interesting.
We will find the
Golden Army here.
As for the crown piece,
I know it's here.
I can feel that much from you.
Father always tried so hard to
shield your heart from mine.
But it's in one of the
books, and I will find it.
Blue.
You always look so
beautiful in blue.
Blue.
Poetry. "Love."
"Found then lost."
Only words. I will find it.
ABE: Listen, listen, Red.
I know what's going on with Liz.
Red.
Abe.
I'm sorry. He has to know.
Abe!
Know what?
(ALARM SOUNDING)
Why?
ABE: Stay back. I'll go first.
Abraham. No, don't...
He'll kill you.
Princess?
NUADA: Abraham?
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
No!
I will kill you, Abraham.
And anyone else if
that is necessary.
HELLBOY: Well?
Then why don't you just start
with me, Your Royal Assness?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Who put those there?
And your weapon of choice?
Five-fingered Mary.
You move and I'll kill
your Abraham first.
Red, you mustn't
harm the Prince.
What?
If you hurt him, you
hurt the Princess.
You've gotta be kidding me.
NUADA: Will you give
me the crown piece?
No.
The piece. No.
Abe?
Red, I'm so sorry,
but they're linked.
JOHANN: What's going on?
Red. Liz.
Red, behind you.
(EXHALES)
You may have mused in the
past, "Am I mortal?"
You are now.
NUADA: Abraham, many people
have died for this crown.
He will, too.
If you want to save him
and see her again,
you will find the missing
piece and bring it to me.
(MACHINE BEEPING)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
Jesus, Abe, pull the
damn thing out!
I cannot.
Every time I touch it, every
time I come close to it,
it moves closer to his heart.
I don't know what else to do.
The wound will not heal
until the spear is removed.
We're running out of time.
Then we go after the Prince.
And we make him take it out.
Hey, Liz.
You were asking me.
Don't talk.
No, no, let me tell you.
I know what's important.
It's you.
Red.
I could turn my back on
the world, all of it,
as long as you stay with me.
I'll stay with you.
You're the best man
I've ever met.
"Man ."
NUALA: "Be near me
when my light is low."
"When the blood creeps."
"And the heart is sick and all
the wheels of being slow."
JOHANN: The cylinder
yielded coordinates
to County Antrim,
Northern lreland.
The Giant's Causeway.
Right about here.
Great. So we know where he is.
What are we waiting for?
We should get going.
The Prince will demand the
crown piece, Agent Sherman.
So we give it to him.
Dr. Manning?
I'm afraid it's not
as simple as that.
Hold on here, what
are you saying?
The Golden Army must not awaken.
LIZ: So, what?
You're just gonna let
him die, is that it?
JOHANN: I'm sorry.
We called Washington.
We have our orders.
And what about you?
He saved your life.
I know.
I know this is difficult
for you, but...
Well, I won't let him die.
Agent Sherman, may I remind you
that I am the leader
of this team.
Oh, there's no doubt
about that, sir.
That is what you
are, Dr. Krauss.
And if ever you were human,
that time is long gone.
MANNING: What's
wrong with her?
You want me to call
her back, sir?
Let her go.
I understand.
What about you?
You find anything?
No. Nothing yet.
Well, keep looking.
Absolutely, sir.
All of you.
But don't worry, sir, we know it's
here, and we're gonna find it.
When Tom Manning gets on
the case, things get done.
They get done. They get done!
100% . I guarantee that.
Even without the piece, we
have to get him out of here.
We'll go to Antrim, and
we will find the Prince.
MANNING: Keep looking.
I ask you, everybody,
keep looking.
Abe.
Just the two of us.
Yes. Yes.
Let's go.
We need to leave now, before
they run our clearance upstairs.
Guten Abend, meine Freunde.
Do you have authorization
to take that plane?
You're not gonna
stop us, Johann.
On the contrary, I've been
giving it some thought,
and we should be able
to save Agent Hellboy.
You say I'm not human
anymore, but you are wrong.
I understand your
pain all too well.
A long time ago, I lost
the woman I loved.
And that was, in fact, the
source of my present misfortune.
I will tell you
about it one day.
But for now, the tactical
advantage is ours.
Consider this, the Prince
lacks the crown piece
and without it, his
army poses no threat.
So we have clearance, then?
Agent Sherman, Liz,
screw the clearance.
We will take that plane!
It should be here someplace.
The entrance should be here.
I don't understand.
JOHANN: Perhaps there's
a mistake on the map.
GOBLIN: Hello there!
I bid you welcome, strangers.
How can I be of assistance?
We seek safe passage
to Bethmoora.
And what does a nice little girl
like you want in the nightlands?
We are looking for Prince Nuada.
Him, I know.
Trade me something, and
I'll take you to him.
Here. I have a shiny belt.
But I have no pants.
Look, a wonderful
set of magic eyes.
I already have binoculars.
But I see something special, something
shiny underneath the bandages.
I want that.
No, you can't take it out.
Not without killing him.
Maybe I know someone who can.
Will you trade me then?
All right.
Very well.
Keep going. Keep going.
Oh, my God.
GOBLIN: You should have seen
this city when it was alive.
What happened to it?
GOBLIN: Curse.
As soon as the Golden
Army was stored here,
a plague of silence
and death befell us.
And the world left us behind.
GOBLIN: For a long time, I
alone dwelled in the dust.
All right, little girl, the
two of you come inside.
The rest of you, wait out here.
Hello, old friend.
I have brought you visitors.
And I have a favor to ask you.
I owe no favor to you, goblin.
Leave.
GOBLIN: But I have
done so much for you.
I have brought you
many souvenirs.
And he has something shiny.
Red.
GOBLIN: Something mine.
Red!
(GROANS)
Anung un Rama.
You know that name?
And yours. Elizabeth Sherman.
(LAUGHING)
At last.
I have been waiting for you
both many a winter moon.
I am his death,
and I will meet him
at each crossroads.
Good. But when can I
have that which is mine?
Can you save him?
It is for you to decide that.
It is all the same to me.
My heart is filled
with dust and sand,
but you should know
it is his destiny
to bring about the
destruction of the Earth.
Not now, not tomorrow,
but soon enough.
Knowing that, you still
want him to live?
So, child, make the choice.
The world or him?
Him.
The time will come
and you, my dear,
will suffer more than anyone.
I'll deal with it.
Now save him.
It is done.
(LAUGHS)
I have done what I can.
Now, give him a reason to live.
Hey, friend, what about
that which is mine?
Don't forget about me.
What about me?
Friend?
Shiny.
Listen to me, you big ape.
You have to get up.
'Cause you're gonna be a father.
I become
father?
Well, all this is very touching,
but if you still want to meet
Nuada, we have to leave now.
Ready.
Here we are.
And there they are.
Seventy times 70 soldiers.
Sometimes I wish I'd
never created them.
Bim-bam went the hammers!
Whoosh went the furnaces!
And one of those fires
took my legs off, now.
This is as far as I can go.
I'm not very good with steps.
But if you're here to stop him,
the Prince, I wish you luck then.
The Golden Army must not awaken.
Undo what we did.
We will.
NUADA: You're here.
So I assume you brought
the remaining piece.
JOHANN: No. We didn't,
but we should discuss...
I'm not addressing you, Tin Man.
Abraham.
Abraham?
My sister is well as
I promised, so...
Abe?
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
What the hell are you doing?
You would do the
exact same for Liz.
JOHANN: Agent Sapien, no!
I am Prince Nuada, Silverlance,
leader of the Golden Army.
Is there anyone here who
would dispute my right?
Kill them.
But...
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
He lied to us.
Abe, old buddy, if we ever get
out of this, we gotta talk.
Open wide!
Industrable, my ass.
(ROARING)
Hey! Throw me a bone here!
Oh, crap.
JOHANN: Well, I'm
out of ideas.
I got one.
I challenge Prince Nuada
for the right to
command this army.
You challenge me?
Who are you to challenge me?
You are nobody.
You are not royalty.
Yes. Yes! He is Anung un
Rama, son of the Fallen One.
He has the right.
A challenge must be answered.
Very well then.
Red, please. Red.
Think about it.
Guys. Guys! He will kill you.
Don't do this, Red.
Don't worry, babe.
I'm not gonna kill him, Abe.
But I am gonna kick his ass.
Whoa!
Red.
Hey!
Nice ride, huh?
You jumpy, slippery bastard.
I got you now.
(GASPING)
Kill me. You must,
for I will not stop.
I cannot. Sorry, pal.
I win.
You live.
Nuala.
The humans,
they will tire of you.
They have already
turned against you.
Leave them.
Is it them or us?
Which holocaust
should be chosen?
I never had a chance to
tell you how I felt.
Give me your hand.
It's beautiful.
We die
and the world will
be poorer for it.
Nuala, my sister.
All that power.
Don't even think about it.
MANNING: No.
No, it's nothing.
I told you, it's a dead end.
What are you doing? Go away.
Check the belt locator.
Check the belt
locators, over there.
Over there.
You, you took that plane without
an authorization, young man.
Hey. Manning.
Here to help as always.
What's going on?
I quit.
What? Are you serious?
Looks that way, doesn't it?
What's wrong with you?
You can't all just quit.
Watch us.
On second thought,
I think I'll keep this.
Come on. Come on!
Johann, they can't do this.
Stop them.
Dr. Manning, suck my
ectoplasmic schwanzstucker.
LIZ: So what you said before,
about us living anywhere.
MANNING: Guys. Guys!
Anywhere. You and me.
MANNING: Come on back.
Let's find a place
in the country.
I said come on back.
Clean air. Green hills.
A yard with lots of
room to grow in.
It'll be great for the baby.
Babies.
Improved By: Fidel33